Akmal Munggaran

akmalmunggaran42@gmail.com | +62 85156985695 | github.com/akMALE21 | linkedin.com/in/akmalmunggaran/

SUMMARY

I graduated in Information Systems and Technology from Institut Teknologi Bandung, with a strong interest in **Data Analyst**, **Data Engineer**, and **Data Science**. Equipped with excellent communication skills and a passion for multifaceted problem-solving, I am committed to advancing my expertise and contributing to impactful projects in data analytics, engineering, and science.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PT. Enseval Putera Megatrading Tbk

Data Engineer Intern

Sep 2024 - now

- Developed and optimized **ETL processes** using **Prefect** in **Python**, managing over **10**+ ETL pipelines to ensure efficient data extraction and transformation.
- Perform data processing and build data extraction procedures using **Oracle**, **Mssql**, **Postgresql**, and **Mysql**, improving the efficiency of data retrieval processes.
- Conducted **market basket analysis** using the **Apriori Algorithm** to optimize warehouse storage layouts based on purchasing patterns and perform simulation using **Anylogic**.
- Prepared over **20** data documentation files using metadata tools, simplifying future data validation and tracking processes.

PT. Oviatech Prima Integra

Data Engineer Intern

Jul 2023 - Feb 2024

- Involved in the development of **5 BI dashboards** for a banking project using **Tableau**.
- Built over 10 data sets leveraging ETL processes for dashboard development using Pentaho Data Integration.
- Contributed in data preparation for the data sources.

EDUCATION

Institut Teknologi Bandung

Aug 2020 - Oct 2024

- Bachelor of Information System and Technology (GPA: 3.40 / 4.00)
- Cloud Computing Cohort at Bangkit Academy led by Google, Tokopedia, Gojek, & Traveloka
- Relevant Coursework: Database Modeling, Database Management, Algorithm and Data Structure, System Requirement Analysis, Resource Management, Software Engineering, Object Oriented Programming

ORGANIZATION AND VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCES

Head of Culture Engagement

HMIF ITB

May 2023 - May 2024

- Establishing HMIF ITB as a student organization with a strong and distinct identity
- Developing a **culture** that aligns with and is relevant to the values of HMIF ITB
- Ensuring the continuity and sustainability of the existing **organizational culture**

Vice Head of Arkavidia Academya

Arkavidia 8.0

Oct 2022 - Mar 2023

- Created a **bootcamp** with 2 learning paths, data science and product management.
- Successfully gained more than 150 registrants.

Head Of Event Organization

The Initiator 2021

Jul 2021 - Sep 2021

- Organized a talk show starring 2 speakers.
- Secured over **500 participants**.

PROJECTS

- Snacktify (2023). Mobile application that helps people identify recipes and nutritional content of food by simply using their smartphone camera. GCP, Python, FastAPI, App Engine, HTML, CSS, JS.
- **Furniture Recommendations API** (2023). Creating a FlaskAPI for furniture recommendations based on the room size of a house. **Python, ElephantSQL, Docker, Microsoft Azure.**
- Electronic Ticketing Integrated System (E-TIS) (2022). Integrated software that has the main function of ordering tickets in an amusement park or playground. HTML, CSS, JS, Python.

SKILLS

Soft Skill: Public Speaking, Leadership, Innovation, Problem Solving, Teamwork, Fast Learner **Tech Stack**: Python, SQL, Pentaho Data Integration, Oracle, Tableau, SQL, Javascript, Postman, FastAPI, GCP, NoSQL